{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The number of members of the division Phaeophyta that live in freshwater habitats", "opta": "is greater than the number of members of the division Chloro-phyta that live in freshwater habitats", "optb": "is lesser than the number of members of the division Chlorophyta that live in freshwater habitats", "optc": "is equal to the number of members of the division Chlorophyta that live in freshwater habitats", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "All members of photolithotrophic autotrophs are also members of algae, but not all members of algae are members of photolithotrophic autotrophs", "optb": "All members of algae are also members of photolithotrophic autotrophs, but not all members of photolithotrophic autotrophs are members of algae", "optc": "All members of photolithotrophic autotrophs are members of algae, and all members of algae are members of photolithotrophic autotrophs", "optd": "No member of photolithotrophic autotrophs is a member of algae", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bioluminescence is a phenomenon associated with", "opta": "chrysophyta", "optb": "phaeophyta", "optc": "pyrrophyta", "optd": "chlorophyta", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following algal divisions is characterized by possession of chlorophylls A and B, starch as the energy storage material, cellulosic cell walls and live in freshwater and marine habitats?", "opta": "Chlorophyta", "optb": "Chrysophyta", "optc": "Phaeophyta", "optd": "Pyrrophyta", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which algal division is divided up into three main groups consisting of the golden-brown algae, the yellow-green algae and the diatoms?", "opta": "Chlorophyta", "optb": "Chrysophyta", "optc": "Phaeophyta", "optd": "Pyrrophyta", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Zooxanthellae are algal symbiont that live within coral reef animals. These algae belong to", "opta": "chlorophyta", "optb": "chrysophyta", "optc": "pyrrophyta", "optd": "rhodophyta", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All algae possess", "opta": "nuclei", "optb": "chloroplasts", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Algae is a nonvalid taxinomic term that refers to", "opta": "eukaryotic organisms that have chlorophyll a and produce O2", "optb": "well developed cellular structure including a conducting system", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following algal divisions is characterized by possession of chlorophylls A and B, paramylon as the energy storage material, and the presence of a pellical instead of a cell wall?", "opta": "Chlorophyta", "optb": "Euglenophyta", "optc": "Pyrrophyta", "optd": "Chrysophyta", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Laminarin is an energy storage material characteristic of", "opta": "chlorophyta", "optb": "chrysophyta", "optc": "phaeophyta", "optd": "pyrrophyta", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chlamydomonas and Volvox are similar because", "opta": "they both are motile", "optb": "they are members of the Chlorophyta", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Characteristics used to place algae into divisions include all of the following except", "opta": "form of storage material", "optb": "flagella number and location", "optc": "accessor pigments used in photosynthesis", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which algal division never produces motile, flagellated cells among any of its members?", "opta": "Chlorophyta", "optb": "Chrysophyta", "optc": "Phaeophyta", "optd": "Rhodophyta", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Starch is an energy storage material characteristic of", "opta": "chlorophyta", "optb": "chrysophyta", "optc": "phaeophyta", "optd": "rhodophyta", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Number of flagella produced by motile cells in", "opta": "members of the phaeophyta is greater than members of the Oomycota", "optb": "members of the Oomycota is greater than members of the Phaeophyta", "optc": "members of the Phaeophyta is approximately equal to members of the Oomycota", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The algae Chlamydomonas demonstrates a complex life cycle that switches between haploid and diploid forms. This life cycle is called", "opta": "the sexual-asexual exchange", "optb": "the transposition cycle", "optc": "an alternation of generations", "optd": "algal transformation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of flagella produced by motile cells in", "opta": "members of the Rhodophyta is greater than members of the Phaeophyta", "optb": "members of the Phaeophyta is greater than members of the Rhodophyta", "optc": "members of the Rhodophyta is exactly or approximately equal to members of the Phaeophyta", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Algae are classified into 6 groups, technically known as", "opta": "categories", "optb": "divisions", "optc": "genera", "optd": "domains", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The __________ is the vegetative body of algae.", "opta": "mycelium", "optb": "plasmodium", "optc": "pseudoplasmodium", "optd": "thallus", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Agar, which is the solidifying agent in many bacterial culture media, is part of the cell wall of", "opta": "chlorophyta", "optb": "chrysophyta", "optc": "pyrrophyta", "optd": "rhodophyta", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The kelps are algae found in", "opta": "chlorophyta", "optb": "chrysophyta", "optc": "phaeophyta", "optd": "pyrrophyta", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Frustules made of silica are characteristic of", "opta": "euglenoids", "optb": "diatoms", "optc": "desmids", "optd": "seaweeds", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Algae are found in all of the following places except", "opta": "oceans", "optb": "soils", "optc": "lakes and streams", "optd": "associates with fungi", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best describes the algae known as diatoms?", "opta": "Cells have intricate shells of silicon dioxide with two halves", "optb": "Cells are encased in rigid walls composed of cellulose coated with silicon", "optc": "Cells have flagella and a light-detecting eye spot", "optd": "Cells contain carotenoid pigments as well as chlorophyll A and B", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chrysolaminarin is an energy storage material characteristic of", "opta": "chlorophyta", "optb": "chrysophyta", "optc": "phaeophyta", "optd": "rhodophyta", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}